# Fedor Lisin

### **Data Scientist**

Moscow, Russia RU

↑ TheoLisin ② @TedFox in theo-lisin

It took me around two years to realise that I like programming in general and data science in particular. Since taking the Yandex classes, well-written, readable code has become my intention. My current focus is creating products that benefit or facilitate the lives of people, not just reviewers.



#### WORK EXPERIENCE (2)

Python Developer at Supervisely OÜ

2023 - 2023

Create a new app on the Supervisely platform and provide client tech help.

- Developed new SOTA model training and serving applications for the Supervisely ecosystem (PIPs, YOLO, MMDetection, MixFormer etc.).
- Enhanced capabilities of the SDK: support for point and object tracking with NN models and linear interpolation
- Provided platform users with technical support

Junior Data Scientist at OCRV, Russian Railways affiliated company

2021 - 2022

Developed different models from scratch for tabular data and time series, upgraded the current data infrastructure, supervised the students' self-study pet projects.

- Train delay investigation system: improving data infrastructure, time to create the final dataset was at least cut in half. (Catboost, SQL, ClickHouse)
- EEG motor imaginary classification: examining the primary methods for getting, classifying, and filtering EEG data, as well as developing experimental data collection methods. (ICA, SSP, WPD)
- Recommendation system for ticket sales (students project): aided students in using their repository and fixed django framework issues. (Git, Conda, Django)

Voice emotion recognition using Wav2Vec

2021 - 2021

https://github.com/TheoLisin/Emotion\_Recognition\_with\_Wav2Vec

Wav2Vec transformers telegram-api

Speech emotion recognition model based on Wav2Vec with telegam-bot user interface.

- Trained 8-class classifier on RAVDESS dataset using Wav2Vec pre-trained model.
- Developed a Telegram bot to gather more data and test the model on Russian speech.

Monotone Hurwitz numbers in genus zero

2019 - 2020

mathematical physics graph theory

University-authored bachelor's thesis

## **EDUCATION (2)**

Bachelor Theoretical Physics at St. Petersburg Academic University of RAS

2016 - 2020

Data Science, MLOps at MADE Data Academy

2022 - 2023

### **CERTIFICATES**

Machine learning | course authored by Stanford University

Coursera, Stanford University

2020-07-25

https://coursera.org/share/fcf17fea90f4868b828c71c2cad3ff7c

## **Machine Learning Engineer**

MADE Data Academy

2023-07

## LANGUAGES

**English** Russian Intermediate Native Speaker

## **INTERESTS**

**Games** 

**Airplanes** 

**Traveling** 

PPL